I never dreamed before
I'm gonna knock the door
into the world of perfect free
(You ain't no lonely!)
You're gonna say I'm lying
I'm gonna get the chance
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
You are the sun, you are the star
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
（平(たいら)）で どうだった？
So, how was it?
やっぱ:too/also|still, おっかない:frightening/scary|extreme
（竜介(りゅうすけ)）
やっぱ おっかなかったぞ
Pretty scary, that Leon Sykes.
レオン・サイクス
グレイ:grey (gray), トフル:Test of English as a Foreign Language/TOEFL, サウンド:sound, 出る[でる]:to leave|to leave (on a journey)|to move forward||
（千葉(ちば)）グレイトフル
サウンドに出れんのか 俺たち？
Will we be able to go on at Grateful Sound?
とりあえず:first of all/at once|for now, 検討[けんとう]:consideration/examination/investigation
（竜介）とりあえず
検討してみるってさ
He said he'd have to look into it.
検討[けんとう]:consideration/examination/investigation
（平）検討… か
Look into it, huh?
旅費[りょひ]:travel expenses, 立て替える[たてかえる]:to pay an advance/to put down money on something|to pay for another
（千葉）おい 旅費
立て替えてやった分—
Just make sure you pay back the money
今月[こんげつ]:this month, 返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
今月中に返せよな
for your expenses within this month, okay?
金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal, エリカ:erica/heath
あいつ 金のためなら
エリカ・ブライジも—
He's the kind of guy who'd
kill Erica Blige for money.
殺すような男だからな
用心[ようじん]:care/precaution/guarding, かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
（竜介）ああ 用心して
かからないと—
Yeah...I'll be careful.
命取り[いのちとり]:fatal/deadly/mortal, かねる:to be unable to/to find difficult (unpleasant, awkward, painful) to do|to serve two or more functions or roles simultaneously
命取りに なりかねねえよな
Don't want to lose my life over that.
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|, 旅費[りょひ]:travel expenses
（千葉）とにかく
早く返してね～ 旅費
Anyways...Pay it back quickly, okay?
安心[あんしん]:relief/peace of mind, 安心[あんじん]:obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice
（竜介）へヘッ 安心しろ
Hmph. Don't worry. I'm not
getting bumped off just yet.
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||
そんなに急に
殺されたりはしねえよ
返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|, 旅費[りょひ]:travel expenses
（千葉）返せよ 旅費
Just pay it back, 'kay?
買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir
（コユキ）
これ 弘美(ひろみ)ちゃんが買ったの？
Hiromi-chan, you bought all these?
古本屋[ふるほんや]:second hand bookstore (bookshop)
（益岡(ますおか)）
うん！ 古本屋だけど—
Yeah, they're from a used-book store,
いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full, 曲[きょく]:song/tune/composition, 曲[くま]:corner/nook|a shadow, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|, 弾く[はじく]:to flip|to repel|to use (an abacus)|, 弾く[ひく]:to play (piano, guitar), まくる:to turn up/to roll up (e.g. sleeves)|to do relentlessly
これで いっぱい曲 覚えて
弾きまくろうかな～って
but now I can learn lots of songs,
and play my heart out.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), やる気[やるき]:willingness (e.g. to do something)/eagerness/motivation
（サク）すごい やる気だね
You're really into it.
ギター:guitar, 本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, 弾ける[はじける]:to burst open|to be bursting with (e.g. youth, laughter, flavor)|to bounce
エヘッ ギター１本 持ってて
弾けないのって—
I'll look bad if I owned a guitar
and couldn't play a tune.
カッコ:parentheses/brackets, カッコ:shape/form/figure, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
カッコ悪いでしょ？
Yeah.
本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||, にくい:hateful/abominable|amazing, にくい:difficult to .../hard to ...
（益岡）でも こういう本
分かりにくくて
But these books are so hard to read...
あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence), 本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||, 当てにする[あてにする]:to count on/to expect someone to (provide help, etc.)
（コユキ）あんまり本を
当てにしないほうがいいよ
I wouldn't depend on these books entirely.
間違う[まちがう]:to make a mistake/to be incorrect/to be mistaken
間違ってるとこも多いし
There are lots of mistakes here.
曲[きょく]:song/tune/composition, 曲[くま]:corner/nook|a shadow, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|
（益岡）えっ じゃあ どうやって
曲を覚えるんですか？
Huh? Then how am I supposed to learn?
うーん:hmm/well, 実際[じっさい]:practicality|reality|bhutakoti (limit of reality), 曲[きょく]:song/tune/composition, 曲[くま]:corner/nook|a shadow, 耳[みみ]:ear|hearing|edge|, 聴く[きく]:to hear|to listen (e.g. to music)|to ask||
うーん 実際に曲を耳で聴いて—
Well, it's best to listen to
the songs and then copy them.
コピー:copy/photocopy
コピーするのが
いいんじゃないかなあ
それぞれ:each/respectively
人それぞれとは思うけど
But I think it's up to the individual.
場合[ばあい]:case/situation, コードブック:code book, 買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir
俺の場合は まず
コードブックを買ってきて—
For me, I'd get a book
on how to play chords,
ひたすら:nothing but/earnest/intent, コード:code, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|, まくる:to turn up/to roll up (e.g. sleeves)|to do relentlessly
とにかく ひたすら
コードを覚えまくったよ
and practice that like heck.
指[ゆび, および]:finger/toe/digit, 指[さし, サシ]:between (e.g. two people)|hindrance|arrhythmic section of recitative in noh music||, 押さえる[おさえる]:to pin something down|to seize|to gain control of something|, 書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
それって 指の押さえるところ
書いてあるのですか？
Would those books show the
finger placement of the chords?
押さえる[おさえる]:to pin something down|to seize|to gain control of something|, 鳴らす[ならす]:to ring|to be popular|to state|, ジャーン:clash/bang, 和音[わおん]:chord|(Japanese) on reading|Japanese music
（コユキ）うん 押さえて鳴らすと
ジャーンって和音が出るやつ
Yup, you press the strings and strum.
場合[ばあい]:case/situation, ひたすら:nothing but/earnest/intent, 地道[じみち]:steady/honest/sober, コード:code, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|, まくる:to turn up/to roll up (e.g. sleeves)|to do relentlessly
俺の場合は とにかく ひたすら
地道にコードを覚えまくった
I just practiced learning those chords.
耳[みみ]:ear|hearing|edge|, コピー:copy/photocopy
（益岡）そしたら 耳コピーとか
できるように なるんですか!?
Then were you able to
learn the songs by ear?
うーん:hmm/well, 周り[まわり]:circumference/girth|surroundings
（コユキ）うーん あと
周りの人に—
Ahh...Well, I did ask others too.
ながら:while/during|while
聞いたりとかしながらかな
やっぱり:too/also|still, 天才[てんさい]:genius/prodigy/natural gift
（益岡）すごーい やっぱり
コユキ君って 天才ですっ！
That's incredible!
You are a genius, Koyuki-kun!
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train
そっ そうかな 普通だと思うけど
Oh-oh yeah? I think I'm pretty ordinary.
かなり:considerably/fairly/quite, 耳[みみ]:ear|hearing|edge|
でも コユキは かなり
耳がいいと思うよ
I'd still say you've got a good ear though.
地道[じみち]:steady/honest/sober, コツコツ:unflaggingly/steadily/untiringly
とにかく 地道に
コツコツ かな？
Anyway, practice makes perfect, I guess.
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 天才[てんさい]:genius/prodigy/natural gift
どんな天才でも—
I don't care how gifted you may be,
いきなり:abruptly/suddenly/all of a sudden, うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
いきなり うまくなったわけじゃ
ないと思うんだ
you don't just wake up
one day knowing all this.
そうかなあ
You really think so?
取り柄[とりえ]:worth/redeeming feature/merit
俺 ほかに取り柄ないし
I...really don't have
much else I'm good at,
ギター:guitar, 弾く[はじく]:to flip|to repel|to use (an abacus)|, 弾く[ひく]:to play (piano, guitar), 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
ギター弾くの 楽しいし
and I love playing the guitar...
弾く[はじく]:to flip|to repel|to use (an abacus)|, 弾く[ひく]:to play (piano, guitar), 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant, 一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree
弾くのが嫌になったこと
一度もないな
And I've never once
gotten tired of playing.
一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree
あ 一度はあるかな…
Well, maybe just once...
（益岡・サク）アハッ
Uh! Yeah!
You open up the door
with negative aura
You say future is murky indeed...
なくす:to lose something|to get rid of
（コユキ）ルシールを
なくした竜介君は—
-Without Lucille,
-You say future is murky indeed...
-I'm sick of hearing gripe.
カスタム:custom/made or built to order
レスポールカスタムを
使っている
-Ryusuke now plays on a custom Les Paul.
-I'm sick of hearing gripe.
-Open up the door with negative aura
やはり:too/also|still, 音[おと, ね]:sound|note|fame|, かなう:to come true (wish)|to be suited
やはり ルシールの音には
かなわないし—
-But still, it's not Lucille,
-Open up the door with negative aura
-If you never change
不満[ふまん]:dissatisfaction/displeasure/discontent, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, 元[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 元[げん]:unknown (e.g. in an equation)|element (of a set)|yuan (monetary unit of China)|
竜介君も不満げだけど
竜介君の作ったリフを元に—
-and Ryusuke isn't entirely satisfied.
-I think there is no way my life
-From our jam sessions
based on Ryusuke's riffs,
-fizzle out
ジャム:jam, 完成[かんせい]:complete/completion|perfection, ブレイン:brain (organ), ストーム:storm
みんなでジャムって完成させた
「brainstorm(ブレインストーム)」
we've come up with
this song, "Brainstorm."
-This is our most powerful
-You open up the door
with negative aura
曲[きょく]:song/tune/composition, 曲[くま]:corner/nook|a shadow, 今まで[いままで]:until now/so far/up to the present, 一番[いちばん]:number one|best|game||, 一番[ひとつがい]:pair/couple/brace, 攻撃的[こうげきてき]:offensive/aggressive, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
この曲は 今までで
一番 攻撃的な すごい曲だ
-and best song yet.
-(I'm fed up fed up fed up)
-And best song yet.
-You say future is murky indeed...
I'm sick of hearing gripe.
Open up the door with negative aura
(I can't keep up with you)
I think there is no way my life
-Fizzle out
-Should we release a new CD by this Fall?
秋[とき]:time|occasion|chance||, 秋[あき]:autumn/fall, 新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
秋までに 新しいＣＤ 作ろっか
-Fizzle out
-Should we release a new CD by this Fall?
-What!?
（千葉）おい 竜介～
Hey, Ryusuke!
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, 曲[きょく]:song/tune/composition, 曲[くま]:corner/nook|a shadow
（平）俺たち 全然
持ち曲ないんだぜ？
We don't have any feature songs.
You want to do a collection of covers?
カバー:cover/covering/dust jacket, アルバム:album
（千葉）何だよ カバー
アルバムでも やろうってのか？
新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
いや 新しいのを作るんだ
Nah, we're going to make new songs.
Huh?
We made a CD that hit the
top ten college charts in the US,
だいたい:outline/main point|general, だいたい:battalion, 全米[ぜんべい]:all-America/pan-American/all of America, カレッジ:college, チャート:chart
（竜介）だいたいさあ 全米
カレッジチャートの—
トップ:top, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
トップ10に入ってるＣＤ
作ったのに—
印税[いんぜい]:royalty (on book), 悔しい[くやしい, くちおしい]:vexing/annoying/frustrating
印税ゼロって 悔しいだろ？
it'd be sad if we didn't
release a follow-up.
Well, that's your fault!
じゃん:isn't it
（千葉）
それって お前のせいじゃん！
Anyway...
作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
（竜介）とにかく…
ＣＤ 作ろうぜ
Let's make another CD.
Then what are we going to do
about the Grateful Sound thing?
それは そうとさあ—
件[くだん]:the aforementioned/the said|the usual, 件[けん]:matter/case/item
グレイトフルサウンドの件は
どぅ～なってんのよお
連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|
（竜介）
レオンからの連絡は まだないよ
I haven't heard back from Leon yet.
当て[あて]:aim|expectations|something that can be relied upon||
ハ～ァ レオンのヤツ
当てにできんのかねえ～
Geez, I guess we can't
count on Leon, either.
しよう:way/method|(technical) specification, しよう:use/application/employment, じゃん:isn't it
（竜介）
ほかに どうしようもねえじゃん
Well, there's nothing we can do about that.
（千葉）ま そうだけどさっ
Yeah, I know, but still...
よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
（メンバーたち）
よろしくお願いします BECK(ベック)です
-Please come see us! We're Beck!
-Please come see us!
よろしく:well/properly|best regards
BECKです よろしくで～す！
We're Beck. Please come see us!
願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself, やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
（千葉）
お願いしやす ヘヘッ
おねえさん:elder sister|(vocative) young lady, よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself, やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
おねえさん
よろしくお願いしやす
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
（女性１）へ～ BECKだって
（女性２）変なの
They're called "Beck."
That's weird. Couldn't they
come up with a different name?
バンド:band, 思いつく[おもいつく]:to think of/to hit upon|to remember
ほかにバンド名
思いつかなかったのかな
（千葉）
いっつも 思うんだけどさあ—
I've always wondered...
Is it worth passing out these flyers?
効果[こうか]:effect/effectiveness|effects (e.g. sound effects, visual effects, special effects)
こんなん 効果 あんのかねえ～
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 経費[けいひ]:expenses/cost/outlay
（サク）確かに経費も
バカにならないよね
It's true that these expenses do add up.
地道[じみち]:steady/honest/sober, 作業[さぎょう]:work/operation/manufacturing, 大切[たいせつ, たいせち]:important|beloved|careful, 大切[おおぎり]:large cut (e.g. of meat)|last piece of the day's programme/last act of a play
（平）いや こういう
地道な作業が大切なんだ
It's important to get the word out.
If even one person came to
see us because of this flyer,
チラシ:scattering, おもしろい:interesting/fascinating|amusing
チラシを見て
おもしろそうだと思って—
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance
ライブに来てくれる人が
１人でもいたら—
広がる[ひろがる]:to spread (out)/to extend/to stretch, 可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility
そこから広がる
可能性だってあるんだ
that one person could help
spread the word about us.
よろしく:well/properly|best regards, バンド:band
（コユキ）よろしく！ 俺たちの
バンド BECKっていいます
Hi there! Our band's call Beck!
Please come see us play!
遊びにくる[あそびにくる]:to come and stay/to drop in/to visit, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
よかったら
遊びにきてください
ハハハ:ha ha ha (laughter)
（男性）ハハハ 何これ
What the heck's this?
Wow, it's incredible...
バンドマン:band-man (member of a musical band)/bandsman, きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil, 対[たい]:opposite|versus|to (e.g. "winning a game five to three")||, 対[つい]:pair|antithesis|counter for items that come in pairs|
（バンドマン１）こいつらが
きょうの対バンか
So, this is our competition today?
バンドマン:band-man (member of a musical band)/bandsman, ふざける:to joke/to jest|to make fun of
（バンドマン２）BECKだってさ
ふざけた名前だよな
They're called "Beck."
What a joke of a name.
Hey, I read in a magazine...
バンドマン:band-man (member of a musical band)/bandsman, 雑誌[ざっし]:journal/magazine/periodical, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
（バンドマン１）雑誌で読んだぜ～
That kid with the cap there, he had
a bit part in that Dying Breed movie.
キャップ:cap, かぶる:to put on (one's head)/to wear|to be covered with (dust, snow, etc.), 映画[えいが]:movie/film
あの キャップかぶったガキが
ダイブリの映画に—
ちょろっと 出てんだとよ
Oh?
バンドマン:band-man (member of a musical band)/bandsman
（バンドマン２）へえ～
Yeah, heard they got quite
a reception at the Whiskey a GoGo.
バンドマン:band-man (member of a musical band)/bandsman, ゴーゴー:go-go, ゴーゴー:thunderous/rumbling
（バンドマン１）この前の
ウィスキーア・ゴーゴーで—
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 入り[いり]:entering|setting (of the sun)|containing||, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
すげえ 入りだったらしいけどな～
They're probably just a poser band,
flavor of the month.
ミーハー:follower of each new fad, 人気[にんき]:popularity/public favor|condition (e.g. market), 人気[ひとけ]:sign of life/human presence|humanity, 今どき[いまどき]:these days/nowadays|at this time (of the day), バンド:band
どーせ ミーハー人気の
今どきのバンドだろ
It'll be tough for them to
survive here at the Marquee.
生き残る[いきのこる]:to survive
このマーキーで生き残るのは
キツイだろうな
It's survival of the fittest here...
These guys will probably just fade away.
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, 自然[しぜん]:nature|natural|naturally, 淘汰[とうた]:weeding out/elimination (e.g. of unneeded employees)|selection (e.g. natural selection), 消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear, 運命[うんめい]:fate/destiny/lot
どうせ 自然淘汰で
消えてく運命さ
Uh! Yeah!
You open up the door
with negative aura
You say future is murky indeed...
I'm sick of hearing gripe.
淘汰[とうた]:weeding out/elimination (e.g. of unneeded employees)|selection (e.g. natural selection)
こりゃあ 淘汰されんのは…
-We might be the ones...
-I'm sick of hearing gripe.
-Open up the door with negative aura
-Getting shut out.
俺らかも…
-So, what do you think of Beck, Manager?
-If you never change
店長[てんちょう]:shop manager
（マネージャー）
BECK どうすか 店長？
-So, what do you think of Beck, Manager?
-I think there is no way my life
-fizzle out
Looks like they won't be quitting
the live house for a while.
当分[とうぶん]:for the present/currently/presently, ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, ハウス:house, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
当分はライブハウス
やめられそうもねえな
You open up the door
with negative aura
(I'm fed up fed up fed up)
You say future is murky indeed...
I'm sick of hearing gripe.
Hey, did you see that Shibuya one?
女子高生[じょしこうせい]:female high-school student
（女子高生１）ねえ 渋谷の見た？
Yeah, Yoshito's so cool!
女子高生[じょしこうせい]:female high-school student, カッコ:parentheses/brackets, カッコ:shape/form/figure
（女子高生２）うん！
ヨシト カッコいいよね～
I'm totally into him!
ウケる:to receive|to catch (e.g. a ball)|to be struck by (wind, waves, sunlight, etc.)||, アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
マジ ウケた～ アハハ！
"Yoshito-Shibuya Panic"
That must have been
an excellent promotion.
プロモーション:promotion, 最高[さいこう]:most/highest|best
（サク）プロモーションとしては
最高だろうね
Seems like the Grateful Sound
tickets are selling well too.
チケット:ticket, 売れる[うれる]:to sell (well)|to be well known/to be popular, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（コユキ）グレイトフルサウンドの
チケットも売れてるみたい
Shibuya Panic, huh?
パニック:panic
（サク）渋谷パニックか
Sounds like a take on a promotion that
the Stones did long ago in New York.
たぶん:informing, たぶん:perhaps/probably|generous, 昔[むかし]:olden days/former, ニューヨーク:New York (US state, city)
たぶん 昔 ストーンズが
ニューヨークでやった—
プロモーション:promotion, まねる:to mimic/to imitate
プロモーションを
まねたんだろうけど
The Stones, huh?
（コユキ）ストーンズかあ
They're in a whole 'nother league from us.
次元[じげん]:dimension|perspective/point of reference
俺たちとは 次元が違うよね～
Hey, to each his own.
We'll just do things our way.
人は 人さ
やり方[やりかた]:manner of doing/way/method
俺たちには 俺たちの
やり方がある
Huh? Ryusuke-kun!
竜介君～！
Hmm? Oh, Koyuki.
お？ おお コユキかあ
"Shiina Bookstore"
Hmm? Oh, Koyuki.
We were on our way to the Fishing Hole.
釣り堀[つりぼり]:fish pond
（コユキ）今 釣り堀に行こうと
思ってたんだけどさあ
"Shiina Bookstore"
I have something I wanted to give to Maho.
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 渡す[わたす]:to ferry across (e.g. a river)|to lay across|to hand over, ものがある:sentence-ending expression of strong judgement
真帆(まほ)に 渡してほしいものがあって
"Shiina Bookstore"
She's there now.
（竜介）あいつなら 今 いるぞ
"Fishing Hole"
Hey there, Koyuki!
（真帆）お～い コユキ～！
Um, this...It's from my parents.
親[おや]:parent|dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)|founder|, 親[しん]:intimacy|close relative|pro- (e.g. pro-American, pro-Japanese, etc.)
（コユキ）あの～
これ うちの親から
What is it?
（真帆）え 何かな
It's Kishu Ume.
(Pickled plums, Kishu-style)
梅[うめ, むめ]:Japanese apricot (Prunus mume)/Chinese plum|lowest (of a three-tier ranking system), 真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, バクバク:thumping (heart)/banging/pounding, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
（コユキ）紀州(きしゅう)梅 真帆が
バクバク食べてたからってさ
You were gobbling them up the last time.
Thanks.
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
（真帆）ありがとう
Oh, let me introduce you,
she's my classmate, Melanie.
紹介[しょうかい]:introduction/presentation/referral
あっ 紹介すんね
クラスメイト:classmate
クラスメイトのメラニーだよ
F-fine, thank you. How are you?
ファイン:fine, サンキュー:thank you
わっ ファイン サンキュー
ハウ ア～ ユ～？
No one's asking how you're doing!
機嫌[きげん]:humour|safety|in a good mood, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
（真帆）誰もコユキの
機嫌なんて 聞いてねえよっ
おもろい:interesting/amusing
（メラニー）ハハハハッ
おもろいやん あんた
You're funny.
日本語[にほんご, にっぽんご]:Japanese (language)|Japanese as a second language
えっ！ に 日本語…
J-Japanese?
Yeah, despite the way she looks,
Melanie was born in Japan.
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife), 日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 生まれ[うまれ]:birth/birthplace|born in (country, month, imperial era, zodiac year, etc.)
（真帆）ああ こう見えて
メラニーは日本生まれなんだ
She's fluent in Japanese. Don't sweat it.
日本語[にほんご, にっぽんご]:Japanese (language)|Japanese as a second language, ペラペラ:fluent/fluency, 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
日本語ペラペラだから 心配なく
Maho stayed overnight at your place, right?
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed
（メラニー）真帆が この前
あんたんちに泊まったんやろ？
Wasn't her teeth-grinding something else?
歯ぎしり[はぎしり]:involuntary nocturnal tooth grinding/bruxism|grinding one's teeth out of anger or vexation, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
こいつ 歯ぎしり すごくない？
Ah, well...no...
（コユキ）
えっ え いやっ そんな…
Her teeth-grinding is unbelievable!
歯ぎしり[はぎしり]:involuntary nocturnal tooth grinding/bruxism|grinding one's teeth out of anger or vexation, めっちゃ:very/extremely/excessively, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
こいつの歯ぎしり
めっちゃ すごいんやもん
Even Yoshito said so.
この前 ヨシトも言っとった
（コユキ）えっ！
Oh, shut up!
うるさい:noisy/loud|annoying, 話題[わだい]:topic/subject
（真帆）うるさいな 何よ その話題
（メラニー）アハハハ…
Why are you talking about that?
I see...
そっかあ
Huh?
For Maho, it's nothing unusual
to sleep over at a friend's house...
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
（コユキ）真帆にしてみれば—
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, 泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 珍しい[めずらしい]:unusual|new|fine (e.g. gift)
友達の家に泊まるなんて
珍しいことじゃなくて—
I guess I was the only one
getting all nervous over it.
心臓[しんぞう]:heart|guts|central part, バクバク:thumping (heart)/banging/pounding
心臓バクバクしてたのは
俺だけなのか
Americans are so progressive...
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger, 先進国[せんしんこく]:advanced (developed) country/advanced nations, アメリカ:America
さすが 先進国 アメリカ
Huh? Chiba's going to be there?
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（竜介）え 千葉が出んのか？
Yup, he said he'll be on about 10 o'clock.
出番[でばん]:one's turn/one's shift|one's turn on stage, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
うん 出番は10時くらいだって
He said if we mention his name at
the door, they'll let us in for free.
受付[うけつけ]:reception (desk)/information desk|receipt, 千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（平）受付で
千葉の名前 出せば—
入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||
タダで入れてくれるように
しとくってさ
That Chiba...What's he planning?
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), どういう:somehow/how/in what way
（竜介）千葉のヤツ
どういうつもりなんだ？
Ah!
Wake up at 11 in the morning,
the ideal break
Turn off the switch from this rapid speed,
take a quick smoke, instantly hungry
Eat move eat embrace relax embrace
sleep and relax again happiness
Let the tension go mellow today
straight to the brain, simply flow
Turning my ear, the rhythm of
the sound and words-die hard
Right, how is it? This feeling!
He was really in his element, huh.
サマになる:to become good-looking/to start looking appropriate (for something)
あいつ サマになってたな
I wonder if Chiba plans to leave Beck,
and go with this band.
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), 脱退[だったい]:secession/retirement/withdrawal (e.g. from a lawsuit)
千葉君 BECK 脱退して—
本格的[ほんかくてき]:genuine|full-scale|full-fledged
こっちを本格的に
やるつもりなのかなあ
No, this is his way of training.
武者[むしゃ]:warrior, 修行[しゅぎょう, すぎょう]:ascetic practices|training/practice
あいつなりの武者修行だよ
It really bothers him that he's the
only one who didn't see that dream.
例[れい]:custom|said|instance|, 例[ためし]:precedent/example, 夢[ゆめ]:dream, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 気にする[きにする]:to mind (negative nuance)/to care about/to worry
あいつ 例の夢 見てねえこと
すごく気にしてんだぜ
Chiba's the kind of guy who'd go tattoo
"Mongolian Chop Squad" on his back.
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), モンゴリアン:Mongolian (person), チョップ:chop
千葉は モンゴリアン・
チョップ・スクワッドって—
背中[せなか]:back (of body), 彫る[ほる, える]:to carve/to engrave|to tattoo, かねる:to be unable to/to find difficult (unpleasant, awkward, painful) to do|to serve two or more functions or roles simultaneously
背中に彫りかねない
そんな男だからな
What a fool...That Chiba.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
ホント バカなヤツだぜ
We wouldn't fire our band's front man
just because of some dream.
夢[ゆめ]:dream, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, バンド:band
夢のことなんかで
バンドのフロントマン—
クビにする:to fire from a job
クビにするわけ ねえのにな
Yeah.
ギャー:yikes!/eek!/ouch!
ギャー ギャッ ギャッ ギャッ
アギャッ ギャ～
Huh?
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
（コユキ）真帆？
Maho?
よう！
Yo!
あ…
（ペイジ）ア～ホウ
A-ho! A-ho!
ア～ホウ ア～ホウ
（コユキ）ああ～!!
Ah, oh...
おかしい:funny/amusing|strange
（コユキ）おかしいな
That's strange, his wings are clipped,
羽[はね]:feather|wing|blade (of a fan, propeller, etc.)||, 羽[わ, ば]:counter for birds and rabbits, 切る[きる]:to cut|to sever (connections, ties)|to turn off (e.g. the light)||, 遠く[とおく]:far away/distant/at a distance, 飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump
羽 切ってあるから そんなに
遠くへは飛べないはずなんだけどな
so he shouldn't be able
to fly away very far...
出張[しゅっちょう]:official tour/business trip, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（真帆）斎藤(さいとう)さん
いつ 出張から戻るの？
When's Mr. Saito coming
back from his business trip?
あした:morning, あした:tomorrow|near future
（コユキ）あした
Tomorrow...
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
（真帆）コユキって
斎藤さん 好きだよね～
Koyuki, you're really fond
of Mr. Saito, aren't you?
仮[け]:lacking substance and existing in name only/something without substance, 仮[かり]:temporary|fictitious|hypothetical, ギター:guitar, 師匠[ししょう]:master/teacher|coach who owns his stable
（コユキ）そうかなあ まあ
仮にも ギターの師匠だからね
You think so? Well, he is
my guitar instructor after all.
朝ごはん[あさごはん]:breakfast, お母さん[おかあさん]:mother
（真帆）この前 朝ごはんのときに
お母さんが言ってたよ
Your mom was telling me
over breakfast last time...
えっ 何？
Huh? What did she say?
ちっちゃい:tiny/little/wee, 頃[ころ, ごろ]:(approximate) time|suitable time (or condition)|time of year, 頃[けい]:qing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu), 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
幸雄は ちっちゃい頃
ちょっと変わった子で—
That when you were little
you were a bit odd,
将来[しょうらい]:future (usually near)/prospects, 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
将来が心配だったって
and she was worried about your future.
母さん[かあさん, かかさん]:mother|wife (used when speaking to or about one's own wife), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., たまに:occasionally/once in a while
うん 母さん 何か その話
たまにするんだよね
Hmm. Yeah, she says that once in a while.
小さい[ちいさい]:small/little/tiny, 頃[ころ, ごろ]:(approximate) time|suitable time (or condition)|time of year, 頃[けい]:qing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu), 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|
でも 小さい頃のこと
全然 覚えてないんだ
But I don't remember anything
from when I was little.
実感[じっかん]:real feeling/actual feeling|to actually feel
だから 実感ないよ
（真帆）フフッ
So none of the things
she said I did seem real.
机[つくえ, つき]:desk, あがる:to rise/to go up|to enter (esp. from outdoors), あがる:to win a hand, 歌う[うたう]:to sing|to sing (one's praises in a poem, etc.)/to compose a poem, 相当[そうとう]:befitting|considerable|to be worthy of||, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, じゃん:isn't it
机の上にあがって歌ったり
相当 変わってたみたいじゃん
Seems you were strange enough,
climbing on top of the table
and singing and stuff...
平凡[へいぼん]:common/commonplace/ordinary
エヘヘッ
でも今じゃ 平凡な—
Yeah, but now, I'm just
an ordinary, teenage guy.
スケール:scale/vernier, 小さい[ちいさい]:small/little/tiny, ティーンエイジャー:teenager
スケールの小さい
ティーンエイジャーだけどね
それじゃあ 私 行くね
（コユキ）えっ…
Well, I better get going.
Huh?
お母さん[おかあさん]:mother, 梅干し[うめぼし]:umeboshi/pickled ume/pickled plum, お礼[おれい, おんれい]:thanks|manners|bow||, ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly
（真帆）お母さんに 梅干しのお礼
ちゃんと言っといてくれよ～
Make sure you thank your mom
for me for the pickled plums.
ああ うち 来ないの？
Oh, you're not coming over?
きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil, 終電[しゅうでん]:last train, つかまえる:to catch/to arrest/to seize, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
（真帆）きょうは
終電 つかまえて 帰るよ
I'll catch the last train out
tonight to get home.
ドキドキ:thump-thump/bang-bang/pit-a-pat
だってさ コユキと２人だと
ドキドキしちゃって—
'Cause, when I'm alone with you,
I get kinda nervous
あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence), 眠る[ねむる, ねぶる]:to sleep (not necessarily lying down)|to die|to lie idle (e.g. of resources)|
あんまり 眠れないんだもん
and can't sleep too well.
駅[えき]:station, 送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||
あっ… 駅まで送るよ
Uh...I'll walk you to the station.
Uh-huh.
（真帆）コユキ
Koyuki, I don't think
you're just an ordinary guy.
平凡[へいぼん]:common/commonplace/ordinary, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
私は コユキが
平凡な人間だなんて思わないよ
（コユキ）アハッ そうかな？
You think so?
見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
ペイジ 見つかるといいけど
I hope you find Page.
ありがと:Thank you
じゃあね！
（コユキ）ありがと！
Well, see yah!
Thanks. Take care.
気をつける[きをつける]:to be careful/to pay attention/to take care
じゃっ 気をつけて
うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious, 生きていく[いきていく, いきてゆく]:to subsist/to keep on living
（コユキ）俺って
うまく生きていくために—
In order to survive, without realizing it,
間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 周り[まわり]:circumference/girth|surroundings, 合わせる[あわせる]:to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)|to join together|to face||
いつの間にか 周りの人に
合わせるようになってたのかな
I've adapted myself
to society's expectations.
他人[たにん, ひと]:another person|unrelated person (i.e. not related by blood)|outsider, 基準[きじゅん]:standard/basis/criterion, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 人生[じんせい]:(human) life (i.e. conception to death)
他人を基準に生きてたら
その人の人生は—
"If you live life by
other people's standards,
then your life is no longer yours."
That's what Eddy said.
自分のものじゃないって
エディが言ってたっけ
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 真剣[しんけん]:seriousness/earnestness|real sword (as opposed to unsharpened or wooden practice weapon), 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
生きることと 死ぬことを
真剣に考えたら—
If I really thought about what
it means to live life and to die,
まとも:the front|honesty/uprightness, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
まともじゃないのは
今の俺のほうかもしれないな
I may be the one who needs
to reassess things.
ギャー:yikes!/eek!/ouch!
（ペイジ）ギャー アギャギャ…
さえずる:to sing/to chirp/to twitter
（サク）ええっ!?
ペイジがさえずったんだ！
What?! Page was singling along with you?
Then it must be a great song!
名曲[めいきょく]:famous music
それじゃあ 名曲ってことだよ
フレーズ:phrase
（コユキ）でも どうかな
フレーズしかできてないし
Yeah, but I've only gotten
part of the refrain done.
へえ～
Hmm...
全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, 完成[かんせい]:complete/completion|perfection
あいつがいなけりゃ 全部
完成してたと思うんだけど—
If he didn't interrupt, I think I would
have had the whole song finished.
つかまえる:to catch/to arrest/to seize, まったく:really/truly|indeed, イメージ:(one's) image, 湧く[わく]:to well (up)|to appear (esp. suddenly) (sweat, tears, etc.)|to feel emotions form (joy, bravery, etc.)|
ペイジをつかまえたあと
まったくイメージが湧かなくて
But after struggling to
catch Page, it all went away.
浮かぶ[うかぶ]:to float|to rise to surface|to come to mind
浮かぶんだ
It just came to you?
不思議[ふしぎ]:wonder/miracle/strange, 感覚[かんかく]:sense/sensation/feeling
今 思うと 何か
不思議な感覚だったな～
It seems so strange
when I think of it now.
曲[きょく]:song/tune/composition, 曲[くま]:corner/nook|a shadow, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, ホント:truth/reality/actuality, なかなか:very/considerably|by no means (with negative verb)
曲を作ろうとしてたときは ホント
なかなか できなかったのに—
When I was trying to compose
a song, I couldn't at all.
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||, メロディー:melody, 頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||, 鳴る[なる]:to sound/to ring/to resound
急に メロディーが
頭の中で 鳴り出したんだ
Then all of a sudden,
this melody just popped up in my head.
そいつ:he/she|that, 聴く[きく]:to hear|to listen (e.g. to music)|to ask||, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
（サク）それじゃあ そいつを
聴かせてもらおうかな
Well, let's hear it!
Okay.
作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
今の… 本当にコユキが作ったの？
Koyuki, you really wrote that tune?
Uh-huh.
英語[えいご]:English (language)
（竜介：英語）
〈それじゃ どこ行けばいい？〉
Then, where should I go?
〈そこなら知ってる〉
Okay, I know that. What time?
Okay. I'll be there.
何時[いつ]:when/how soon, 何時[なんじ, なんどき]:what time?
〈何時に行けばいい？〉
〈それじゃ〉
Hey, It's my first time
to ride on a helicopter.
乗る[のる]:to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.)|to get on (e.g. a footstool)|to reach||, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
〈ヘリに乗るのは初めてなんだ〉
〈これをベックに〉
I brought this again, for Beck. Take it.
"Dog Arnold's Bone" [Doggie Treats]
Hey, you fuckin' talk too much.
ゴール:goal/basket (basketball)/finishing line, ディー:D/d, 英語[えいご]:English (language), だまる:to be silent
（ゴールディー：英語）
〈おい だまれ！〉
撃つ[うつ]:to shoot (at)|to attack/to defeat
（竜介）〈撃つなら撃てよ〉
Shoot me if you want, all right?
撃つ[うつ]:to shoot (at)|to attack/to defeat
（ゴールディー）〈ココじゃ
撃てないと思ってるのか？〉
You think I won't shoot you
right here, muthafucker?
Hey, stop it! We're talking business here.
英語[えいご]:English (language), やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
（レオン：英語）〈やめろ！〉
ビジネス:business, 話をする[はなしをする]:to have a talk/to tell a story
〈これから
ビジネスの話をするんだ〉
飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump
〈で どこへ飛ぶんだい？〉
So, where are you going?
北[きた]:north|the North|North Korea|, 北[ペー]:north wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of north wind tiles
（レオン）〈北だ〉
North.
Damn, fucker! Always getting me
in trouble with the boss.
きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
（コユキの母）幸雄！ きょうは
あんたの好きな おでんだよ
Yukio! It's your favorite, stew!
Damn, this fucker's
always doing this shit...
もしもし:hello (e.g. on phone)|excuse me! (when calling out to someone)
（和緒(かずお)）もしもし
おはよっ 誰だか 分かる？
Hello. Good morning.
Do you know who this is?
酒[さけ, ささ]:alcohol/sake, 声[こえ]:voice
（竜介）
そんな 酒やけした声の女は—
There's only one woman that I know
with a whiskey-soaked,
raspy voice like yours.
知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance
俺の知り合いには
１人しかいねえよ
It's been decided.
決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
（和緒）決まったわよ これで—
You guys will be going on
the Grateful Sound stage.
グレイ:grey (gray), トフル:Test of English as a Foreign Language/TOEFL, サウンド:sound
あんたたち グレイトフル
サウンドに出られるわ
Yeah.
There was a real push from Leon.
Even Ran couldn't resist.
強烈[きょうれつ]:strong/intense/severe, プッシュ:push
（和緒）レオンからの
強烈なプッシュがあったの
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger, 蘭[らん, ラン]:orchid|Holland/The Netherlands, 蘭[あららぎ, アララギ]:Japanese yew (Taxus cuspidata)|wild rocambole (Allium grayi), 抵抗[ていこう]:resistance|reluctance|resistance||
さすがの蘭(らん)も
抵抗できなかったわ
Hey Aunty, it's not finalized yet.
決定[けってい]:decision/determination
（竜介）オバチャン それ
まだ決定じゃねえんだ
Huh? What do you mean?
どういう:somehow/how/in what way
（和緒）え？ どういうこと？
バンド:band, メンバー:member/participant/attendee, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
（竜介）バンドのメンバーと
相談して 決めるつもりなんだ
I still have to run it
by the rest of the band.
（和緒）
あんたたち 出たいんでしょ？
But don't you guys want to
perform at Grateful Sound?
グレイトフルサウンド
きのう:function/facility/faculty, きのう:induction/inductive reasoning, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
（竜介）
きのう レオンと会って話した
Yesterday, I met with Leon.
We even went to look at the stage.
会場[かいじょう]:assembly hall/meeting place/venue
会場にも行ってきたよ
So...what happened?
それで どうして…？
条件[じょうけん]:condition/conditions/term, ひどい:cruel/heartless|violent, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time)
（竜介）あいつの出した条件が
ひどすぎるんだ
His terms were way too hard.
I don't think we can go through with it.
たぶん:informing, たぶん:perhaps/probably|generous
たぶん 俺たちは出ないと思う
あの～ 竜介君
Hello, Ryusuke-kun?
What's up? Koyuki, come help me
set up the fishing poles.
針[はり, ち]:needle|hook|stinger||, 付ける[つける]:to attach|to furnish (a house with)|to wear||, 手伝う[てつだう]:to help/to assist|to contribute to
（竜介）どうした～？ コユキ
お前も 針 付けんの手伝え
Umm, I wanted you to listen to this.
聴く[きく]:to hear|to listen (e.g. to music)|to ask||
（コユキ）あのさ これ
聴いてほしいんだ
Hmm. I'm surprised
you wrote such a tune.
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, フレーズ:phrase, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
フッ まさか… お前に
こんなフレーズが作れるとはな
Really?
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
（コユキ）ホント？
But the continuity is off.
展開[てんかい]:development|expansion|expansion, 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
でもな 展開とかは
全然 ダメだけどな
I see.
そっか… んん
All right! I've decided, Koyuki.
決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
（竜介）よしっ 決めたぞ コユキ
Hmm? Decided what?
んっ 何を？
グレイトフルサウンドに出るぞ
We're going to appear at Grateful Sound!
H-Hey! I-I-Is this for real?!
U-Us! Hah-hah!
マジかよ… おっ 俺たちが
アハッ オホホ～ゥ！
-Yeah!
-Dying Breed's not appearing?
ダイブリは 出ないのか
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（千葉）すげえ～！
アハハハハ～！
No, I don't want to trouble Eddy.
迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
ああ エディに迷惑は
かけたくないんだ
I see. So what were Leon's terms?
そうか
条件[じょうけん]:condition/conditions/term
で レオンの出した条件って
何なんだ？
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
（竜介）うん… そのうち話す
We'll talk about it later.
Right now, I just want to focus
on improving the band's skills.
バンド:band, スキル:skill, アップ:increasing, 集中[しゅうちゅう]:concentration/convergence/centralization
今は バンドのスキルアップに
集中したいんだ
Chiba-kun! I'm sure
they'll give you one if you ask.
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), 頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|, もらえる:to be able to receive/to be able to take|could you (give me)
（コユキ）
千葉君 頼めばもらえるよ
Yeah, is that so?
そうかあ ハハッ アハハハハ
（サク）アハッ
You sure like to pilfer stuff.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
（竜介）手グセ 悪いな お前
Shut up, you!
うるさい:noisy/loud|annoying
（千葉）うるせえ このヤロー！
デヘヘヘ…
（竜介）フンッ
An incredible summer...
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 夏[なつ]:summer, 夏[か]:Xia (dynasty of China; perhaps mythological)
（コユキ）すごい夏が—
A really incredible summer
is about to unfold...
めちゃくちゃ:absurd/unreasonable|extreme, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 夏[なつ]:summer, 夏[か]:Xia (dynasty of China; perhaps mythological), やってくる:to come along/to come around|to arrive at the present
めちゃくちゃ すごい夏が
やってくる
Full moon sways
Gently in the night of one fine day
What a fool
I don't know 'bout tomorrow
What it's like to be
Ah...
I was fool
Couldn't let myself to go
Even though I feel
The end
Full moon sways
Smiling in my arms for all those years
We're finally headed North.
ついに:finally/at last|in the end, 北[きた]:north|the North|North Korea|, 北[ペー]:north wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of north wind tiles, 向かう[むかう]:to face|to go towards/to head towards
（千葉）
ついに俺たちは 北へ向かう
Destination: Grateful Sound!
舞台[ぶたい]:stage (theatre, theater)|scene or setting (e.g. of novel, play, etc.), グレイ:grey (gray), トフル:Test of English as a Foreign Language/TOEFL, サウンド:sound
舞台は
グレイトフルサウンド！
"Live 22 'Performance Eve Festival'"
Destination: Grateful Sound!
Next episode, Performance Eve Festival!
Watch it, okay?
次週[じしゅう]:next week, 前夜祭[ぜんやさい]:the eve (of festival) (e.g. Christmas Eve)
次週 「前夜祭」
見ろよなっ